# Peganov Nikita

# **Backend Developer**

Backend developer with working experience in highload systems and project organization. Specialize in Python and Java with 3 years of production development experience. I am fond of creating IT-startups, generating ideas and learning new technologies. I prefer to work in Moscow.

### EXPERIENCE

Yandex, Moscow

February 2023 — Now

Middle Python Developer in Infrastructure L3 Management

- reduced the service status update time from 7 minutes to 1 minute using database denormalization
- ullet developed a collector of metrics about services and balancers, and was responsible for its stability
- integrated mechanism for providing alerts to users that sends alerts within 30 seconds

Yandex, Moscow

July 2022 - October 2022

Intern Python/Java Developer of a compensation calculation system in HR-Tech

- added processing of uploads to the system reducing user work time by 50%
- implemented uploading of all user data to the cloud to increase system fault tolerance
- ullet solved 23 minor tasks and wrote unit tests for them to improve the system

Yandex, Moscow

July 2021 — November 2021

Intern Python Developer in traffic management team

- $\bullet$  reduced by 50% the load on the servers with DB by translating readonly requests to replicas
- added ipv6 processing into balancers' work allowed to use new ip's without extra 900 lines
- created an internal library redirecting the request to the nearest datacenter

## **PROJECTS**

Tinkoff, Moscow

October 2023 — April 2024

Java Developer, Project Manager

Tukach: The system for accepting applications for violations of corporate ethics

- developed a telegram bot for accepting applications that received 90% positive reviews
- assembled a team of 4 programmers and led it, all deadlines were met
- collected the requirements from the customer, came up with several additional ideas

Huawei, Moscow

November 2021 - May 2022

Python Developer, Data Scientist

Research work «Reinforcement learning for resource allocation tasks in the cloud»

- tested the applicability of reinforcement learning in real conditions
- created and trained a neural network processing 4500 requests per hour
- the total number of processed requests was 1.5 million

# Startup SmartLearning, Moscow

November 2020 - March 2021

Kotlin Developer, SEO the development of the Android-application for quick learning

- assembled and managed a team of 4 programmers
- developed an Android application downloaded by 183 users
- took the 19th place at the HSE Fest startup competition

#### **EDUCATION**

# Higher School of Economics, Moscow

Since September 2020

Bachelor in Computer Science

- Graduated courses with excellence: C++ Programming, Introduction to Applied Analytics, Databases, Calculus, Discrete Mathematics, English for Business Purposes
- Completed courses: Operating Systems, Software Design on Java, Algorithms and Data Structures, Computer System Architecture, Algebra, Software Development Methodologies, Probability Theory
- •Research works in the field of neural networks were rated 9 out of 10 by scientific supervisors

Moscow, Russia

t.me/peganov ns

peganov.nik@gmail.com +7 (985) 696-83-57 github.com/NikPeg gitlab.com/peganov.nik

#### COMPUTER SKILLS

Python (Django, Jupyter, numpy, sympy, sklearn)
Java (Sockets, JavaFX,
Multithreading, Derby,
Spring)
C/C++
(Multithreading, STL)
C#

(Requests, Windows forms)

Kotlin (Android)

SQL

(SQLite, PostgreSQL)

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Git
Linux
gRPC
Docker
Selenium
Telegram API
ChatGPT API

#### LANGUAGES

JetBrains IDEs

English (B2) Russian (Native speaker)

### ACHIEVEMENTS

Winner of ITMO "Open

Olympiad of schoolchildren in computer science" (2020) Winner of "United Mathematical Olympiad of schoolchildren" (2020) Medalist of Olympiad of schoolchildren "Fiztech" in mathematics (2020) Medalist of regional stage in All-Russian Olympiad of schoolchildren of

# OTHER COURSES Summer School of Russian

CS and ICT (2019)

Association of Artificial Intelligence (2021) Tinkoff Generation (2019) Samsung IT-school (2018)